<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!DOCTYPE document SYSTEM "./dtd/document-v10.dtd">

<document>
  <header>
    <title>Jesktop.net - Free/Open Applications</title>
    <subtitle>HorstScape</subtitle>
    <authors>
      <person id="PH" name="Paul Hammant" email="Paul_Hammant@yahoo.com"/>
    </authors>
    <notice>
      Jesktop documentation is under construction.  Everything you
      can find outside this page is to be considered obsolete.
    </notice>
  </header>
  <body>
    <s1 title="HorstScape">
      <figure src="images/htmlwindow.gif" alt="htmlwindow"/>
      <p>
        Note - HTMLWindow.jar has been obsoleted from Horst Hiestermann's site (June 2001).  You can't download the component any more....
      </p>
      <p>
	HorstScape is a browser also ported during the summer of 2000 to PJE.  Horst
	Heistermann's excellent HTMLWindow api is wrapped by his own
	demonstration browser "HorstScape".  We took the source for the browser and
	with his permission forked the browser source so that we could get it
	working inside PJE and now Jesktop.  HTMLWindow is commercial software
	(we hope Horst makes his million from it as it's very good).  As such, it
	is unsuitable for a long term choice of browser inside Jesktop.  We
	don't distribute the HTMLWindow jar as it is commercial, but there is a
	readme if you want to see it running.  
      </p>
      <p>
        In January 2001, Horst released a new product called WebWindow that is
        commercial and is doubtless based in his previous body of work.  We wish
        him every sucess with that.
      </p>
    </s1>
    <s1 title="License">
      <p>
	Horst's Browser source is free for reuse, but the rendering component is (or was) commercial.
      </p>
    </s1>
    <s1 title="Main HorstScape Site">
      <p>
	Project home site : <link href="http://home.earthlink.net/~hheister/">http://home.earthlink.net/~hheister/</link>
      </p>
    </s1>
  </body>
  <footer>
    <legal>
      Copyright (c) @year@ The Jesktop Project All rights reserved.
    </legal>
  </footer>
</document>
